My middle school daughter is forgetful
and messy
Hello
I have two daughter, one in 8th grade
and the other in 3rd grade.
The 8th grade daughter
is well behaved at school.
But according to her teachers, she's
seriously forgetful as if she has dementia.
She'd even forget to mark her answers
on exams.
As her symptoms have gotten serious,
she gets upset herself.
She's also too lazy to even take off
her school uniform after school.
Even if she does take it off, she leaves
clothes around the house everywhere.
If I bring snacks to her room, she leaves
them as is without cleaning up after.
If I don't clean them for her,
they remain in her room piled up.
She leaves all her trash laying around.
As these symptoms have gotten serious,
she now forgets to tell me
essential things.
She called me from school today saying,
"Mom, I forgot to bring things for my
school evaluation, can you bring it for me?"
As it gets serious,
I wonder whether I should leave her as is
or chase her around to help her out.
I'm not helping her out at the moment.
While it's becoming a daily battle,
she claims that other moms clean up
after their kids.
To that I told her
I can't do that for her.
Should I continue arguing
over this matter with my child?
Or should I let it go and just pick up
after her?
Which do you prefer?
Would you rather argue
and not clean up after her?
Or would you rather clean up
and not argue with her?
I'd rather clean up after her.
Then do that. Do what suits you best.
(Audience Laughter)
But it's been so long that she
doesn't want to do anything herself.
(Sunim) So?
(Questioner) So...
So which do you prefer?
(Questioner) I'd rather clean up after her,
but I don't think it's good for her
in the long run to do so.
So I'm not cleaning after her
at the moment.
Then either don't clean after her or
just clean after her. Why argue with her?
I feel like
I shouldn't be cleaning for her.
(Sunim) Then don't clean after her.
I'm asking why argue?
It's hard for me.
I'm saying either clean after her
or don't.
Why argue over it?
(Questioner) I don't feel comfortable.
Look within yourself.
Whatever she does,
you can either clean up after her or not.
Why argue over it?
I'd rather clean up after her.
But I do emphasize to her
that she should clean up after herself.
Then she'd argue about it.
Then you can just not clean up after her.
Why nag her?
If you feel like it's not good for your child,
don't clean up after her.
(Questioner) Then should I just leave her
as is?
If you can't stand the mess,
you clean it yourself.
If you can stand the mess, leave it as is.
It's your problem.
It has nothing to do with your child.
You speak as if your child has a problem.
If you'd rather clean up after her, do it.
If you think you shouldn't, then don't.
But why argue with a child?
You're a grown up, she's a child.
Okay.
(Sunim) My point is this.
If you think she's too messy, clean up after her
as a mother without saying anything.
If you think it'll spoil her by doing so,
just leave it as is.
It doesn't matter whether 5 or 7 plates
pile up, just buy more plates.
Leave it there.
Why argue and create conflict with her?
This is what I'm asking you.
(Questioner) I see.
If you don't want to clean up after her,
leave her clothes laying around as is.
Leave the 7 cups stacked as is.
Is she asks why you aren't cleaning it,
you can say, "Oh did I not? I'm just busy,
why don't you clean it yourself?"
You're saying "Why aren't you cleaning up
after yourself?" Hence you argue.
No need to say anything.
If she asks you to bring things for her,
just say,
"Oh you must have forgotten."
"I'm busy myself, you should come
and take it yourself."
(Audience Laughter)
(Questioner) Okay.
I'm saying there's no need
to argue with her.
She's young, she can get frustrated and say,
"Why aren't you doing these things for me?"
To that you can avoid arguing by saying,
"I'm sorry, I'm just busy."
There's no need for you
to argue with a child.
As a mother, do things for her
if you think you need to.
Don't if you feel it's bad for her.
There's no need to argue.
There's no need to say 'do this, do that'.
Tell her once and if she doesn't comply,
just let her be.
If her room gets unbearably messy,
would she clean it eventually or not?
She would.
So if you're running out of plates,
just buy more plates.
(Questioner) Yes, I understand.
There's no need to argue over it.
It makes life easier for you not to.
Now you claim you won't clean up
after her for your child's sake,
but you can't bear the sight of plates
piling up and you clean up after her.
Then that's your problem.
If you really think you shouldn't clean up
after her for your child's sake,
you really shouldn't clean it
whether it's 50 plates piling or more.
You're not really doing it for her sake.
You're going back and forth
based on your own temper.
(Questioner) I understand.
What should a mother do for her child?
A mother should either
attend to her child's needs
without a word, whatever it is.
If a mother thinks
it's bad for the child's sake,
she should leave things
as is until the child can fix her habit.
There's no need to say, "Fix your habit".
Then it leads to an argument.
Even if the child makes a fuss about it,
just say, "Mom is busy.
I can only do so much."
By doing so you can avoid an argument.
Don't clean after her
whether it be 10 days, a month or a year.
Don't pick up her clothes after her,
she'll eventually figure something out.
It's you lacking persistence,
you are causing the problem here.
You have no patience,
hence you're causing the problem.
It's not your child
that is causing the problem.
(Questioner) I understand.
Does this solve your question?
(Questioner) It does, thank you.
I'm not sure
if it solved your question.
(Audience Laughter)
It did, I'll need to think it over
when I get home.
Then you're saying
your question hasn't been resolved.
(Audience Laughter)
Why think it over at home?
You should recognize your fault here
and now.
Why contemplate over it at home?
Hence I'm saying I don't think
I've resolved your question.
Has your question been resolved?
Yes, thank you.
If a child and an adult argues,
who has the advantage?
The adult does, does she not?
Then why do adults keep arguing
with their child?
Why do they? Why fuss over things
with a child?
The child would feel hopeless
and get frustrated and annoyed.
But why should a mother get frustrated?
Don't cook for them
or don't do their laundry.
There are many methods
you can take as a mother.
You have so much more advantage
over them as an adult.
Yet why do you fight your children?
It's like as if the U.S is making
a fuss over fighting North Korea.
Why fuss over it
when you have the advantage?
You can just pull their leg, no?
You can gesture to do things
and not follow through.
You can say, "You have 3 plates piled up,
I'll clean it for you."
And then you can leave them as is.
"You now have 7 plates piled up,
didn't know there were so many."
"I'm a bit busy though,
think you can clean them yourself?"
Make the child worry and fret about it
and act on it eventually.
Why fret over it as an adult?
It's foolish of you to do so.
You're fighting over things
with your own child.
What kind of a mother is that?
Is that an adult thing to do?
You're fighting with a child
because you are a child yourself.
As an adult, you either clean up after her
without a word
or you don't.
It's not a big deal.
If she asks you to bring things to school,
you either bring her things right away,
or you say,
"Okay, I will" and you don't follow
through so that she fixes her habit.
(Audience Laughter)
There's no need to argue over it.
There's no need to say
you won't bring it for her.
Say you will and don't follow through.
If you do this a few more times,
what else can she do
but take care of things herself?
Do you understand what I'm saying?
(Audience) Yes.
Why fret over things
when you're in a favorable situation?